A Guide to the Papers of Herbert Emmerich 1931-1987
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Herbert Emmerich 1931-1987
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12738-d
This collection consists of 36 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given as a gift to the Library on March 21, 1988.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains annual reports, 1939-1954, of the Public Administration Clearing House; some miscellaneous papers of the PACH, including a staff roster, reports to the Board of Trustees, 1931, a study on federal executive reorganization by Emmerich, and a memorandum of a conversation on the war contribution of Sidney Hyman.
It also contains a report on public administration in Venezuela, 1958-1961; an article on international technical assistance; a tribute to Louis Brownlow; recommendations for an M.A. program in public administration at the University of Virginia; copies of student theses awarded the Quincy Wright-Herbert Emmerich prize; and a photograph of Emmerich.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Photograph of Herbert Emmerich n.d. (Box 1)
- Public Administration Clearing House Annual Reports 1939-1945, 6 folders (Box 1)
- Public Administration Clearing House Annual Reports 1946-1954, 9 folders (Box 2)
- Public Administration Clearing House Former "1313" Staff Member Roster 1952 (Box 3)
- Public Administration Clearing House Report to the Board of Trustees 1931 (Box 3)
- Public Administration Papers 1940-1975 (Box 3)
- Public Administration Report on Federal Executive Organization 1964 (Box 3)
- Public Adminstration Reports 1949-1965 (Box 3)
- Quincy Wright-Herbert Emmerich Prize: "Deutschlandpolitk in Transistion.. ." by Andrea C. Wuerth 1986 (Box 3)
- Quincy Wright-Herbert Emmerich Prize: "The Erosion of the Norwegian Security Consensus.. ." by Brant M. Simenson 1987 (Box 3)